Contact

regina_valenzuela@ymail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/reginavalenzuela-acnp-bc-rrtccrn-46bb0448 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

ACLS

PALS

NRP

Certifications

ACLS

CCRN

AGACNP-BC

Regina Valenzuela ACNP-BC, RRT, CCRN,

Cardiovascular Surgery Nurse Practitioner Phoenix, Arizona Area

Summary

Experienced professional with a demonstrated history of working in the hospital & healthcare industry. Skilled in Cardiovascular Nursing, Post Anesthesia Care, Critical Care Nursing, Cardiac Care Nursing, and Mechanical Ventilation. Licenses held include: Acute Care Nurse Practitioner, Registered Nurse, and Respiratory Therapy. Certifications held in Advanced Cardiac Life Support (ACLS) and the American Association of Critical Care Nurses, Critical Care Registered Nurse (CCRN). Strong healthcare services professional with a Master's Degree focused on Acute Care Nurse Practitioner (ACNP-AG) completed in June of 2019. NIFA suture star course attendee. Board Certified ACNP as of July 2019.

Experience

Banner Health 14 years 1 month

Cardiovascular Surgery Nurse Practitioner January 2020 - Present (6 months)

RN -CVICU

February 2013 - January 2020 (7 years)

Care of cardiac and thoracic post-op patients with varying types of hemodynamic monitoring, medication, and medical equipment needs Care of medical intensive care patients

Assesses patient physical, psychological, social, spiritual, educational, developmental, cultural and discharge planning needs.

Reviews diagnostics and laboratory data and reports abnormal results to the physician(s) and other appropriate caregivers.

Formulates a plan of care, including discharge plan, utilizing assessment data and patient, family and health team input.

Initiates a plan of care based on patient-specific needs, assessment data and the medical plan of care in acute setting. Implements the plan of care through direct care, coordination, delegation and supervision of activities of the health care team.

Provides care based on physician orders, nursing plan of care in compliance with policies and procedures, standards of care, regulatory agency requirements, and based on the best evidence available.

Documents assessment, planning, implementation and evaluation in the patient record

Experience/ trained in: Team lead, orientation of new employees, open heart recovery, IAPB, Impella, pacers, TAVR's, and sheath, central line, and MT management and removal.

RN Manager CVICU

July 2016 - October 2019 (3 years 4 months)

RRT Advanced Practitioner

June 2006 - February 2013 (6 years 9 months)

Performing basic modalities and advanced practice pulmonary and cardiology Provide respiratory care/ therapy to patients in all areas to include all inpatient/ outpatient areas: Medical, Neurovascular and Cardiovascular ICU's, OR Cath lab, ER, PACU, SDS, general floors and rehabilitation

Provide patients and family members with education.

Assist physicians with decision making regarding various modalities of patient care.

Provide patient assessment and monitor patient outcome.

Work with team members to help ensure that patients are cared for with needs met.

Providing diagnostic tests such as ABG's, bedside PFT's, EKG's, and Peak Flow.

Provides collaborated ventilator management in response to the patient management..

Assist in acute situations, including airway management and cardiopulmonary resuscitation

Insert and maintenance of arterial lines

Assistance in: bronchoscopy's, cardiac stress tests,' EEG's,TEE,'s cardioversion, and conscious sedation

Assist with surgical procedures such as tracheotomy's, IABP placement, and chest tube's

Provide IAPB patient monitoring, and troubleshooting.

Assist with placement of central lines and pulmonary artery catheter's Experience with use of multiple types of hemodynamic monitoring equipment. A resource to all healthcare practitioners regarding patient status, equipment and operations

HonorHealth

RN- Research Nurse/ Coordinator June 2015 - June 2016 (1 year 1 month)

Cardiovascular Research Nurse

Involved in over thirteen different cardiovascular and electrophysiology clinical trials.

Screen for recruitment of subjects appropriate for entry into the research studies.

Patient and family education.

Advocates for patient and study appropriateness with cohesion of device, medication and/or other requirements.

Discusses and provides information regarding specific study and protocol with subjects and family members.

Obtains informed consent, as requested by the primary investigator while maintaining strict confidentiality.

Performs study treatments as described (physical assessment, drug administration and specimen collection).

Scheduling follow up visits according to protocol specifics.

Ensures study diagnostics and treatments are carried out.

Collects, inputs, and maintains appropriate subject data for studies into databases.

Monitors and reports significant study events.

Provides protocol specifications to principal investigator for understanding protocol requirements.

Education

Grand Canyon University

Master's Degree, MSN ACNP-AG · (2016 - 2019)

Northern Arizona University

Bachelor of Science (B.S.), Registered Nursing/Registered

Nurse · (2014 - 2016)

Mesa / Boswell School of Nursing

Associate of Arts and Sciences (A.A.S.), Registered Nursing/Registered Nurse \cdot (2010 - 2012)

Gateway Community College
Associate of Arts and Sciences (A.A.S.), Respiratory Care Therapy/
Therapist · (2004 - 2006)

Scottsdale Community College Associate of Arts (A.A.) · (1998 - 2000)